SO YOUR PRICES ARE
INCLUDING
ALL THE SURVEY. ALL
THE
PRICES YOU SEE ON
THE WEBSITE INCLUDES
EVERYTHING EXCEPT
FOR SITE WORK
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW
YOUR SITE.
RIGHT. SO I NEED TO
KNOW YOUR
SITE AND THEN I CAN
ADD THAT COST.
BUT FIGURE ANYWHERE
FROM
50 TO 75,000
ADDITIONAL. 50 TO
75. OVER THE PRICE
THAT YOU HAVE.
CORRECT.
FOR THE SITE WORK
AND ALL THE THINGS
THAT HAVE TO HAPPEN.
BUT SOME
LOTS ARE EASY. YEAH.
THIS IS PRETTY FLAT.
YEAH. YEAH. YEAH.
SO I'VE SEEN UNDER
950 SQUARE
FEET OR 50 PERCENT
THE SIZE OF YOUR
EXISTING.
CORRECT. THE WALL
TOWNS,
THEY GET EATEN BY
THAT.
IT IS. BUT TELL
ME ABOUT THE
EXISTING HOUSE
THAT'S
THERE. IT'S PRETTY
SMART. IT'S
900 SQUARE FEET NOW.
BUT DOES IT HAVE A
FULL
BASEMENT? YES.
YES. CAN YOU STAND
UP IN IT?
YES. SO WE
CAN COUNT THAT
SQUARE
FOOTAGE TOWARDS THE
CALCULATION,
FINISHED
OR UNFINISHED, AS
LONG AS IT'S SIX
FOOT
EIGHT FROM THE
CONCRETE FLOOR
TO THE BOTTOM OF THE
FLOOR JOISTS.
I KNOW THEY HAVE THE
WASH AND DRYER
DOWN THERE. I
HAVEN'T MEASURED
IT. WELL, THAT'S
WHAT YOU NEED TO
MEASURE.
YOU NEED TO MEASURE
FROM THE CONCRETE
FLOOR TO THE FLOOR
JOISTS. IF YOU
HAVE ANYTHING OVER
SIX FOOT
EIGHT, WE'RE IN
BUSINESS. AND
ALSO THEY HAVE AN
UPSTAIRS
BEDROOM. DOES THAT
COUNT TOO? YES.
AS LONG AS IT'S SIX
FOOT EIGHT
OR HIGHER. OK.
YEAH.
YEAH. YEAH. OK.
THAT'S GOOD TO KNOW.
YEAH. SO WE'LL
PROBABLY BETWEEN
WELL OUR NEXT STEP
IS
GOING TO BE FINDING
OUT
FROM THE TOWN, WELL
COULD
WE HAVE AN ADU?
NO YOU CAN
ABSOLUTELY HAVE
AN ADU, SO I WOULD
NOT RELY
ON THEM FOR ACCURATE
INFORMATION.
NO, NO, YOU'RE
BETTER OFF TO HAVE
THE ZOOM MEETING
AND AGAIN, ALL
RESPECT TO THEM,
THEY ARE NOT PRO
ADU,
OKAY, SO THE
FLOOR THAT WE'VE
PERMITTED IT HAS
IN THIS AREA, DO WE
HAVE TO PUT IN A
FOUNDATION
FOR FROST? WE DO.
FOUR FEET.
YEAH. WELL,
THIS WOULD HAVE A
SLAB FOR THE
GARAGE. BUT IF YOU
DON'T
DO A GARAGE UNDER,
WE WOULD
DO A CRAWL SPACE FOR
A CROSS
GEAR. SO IF WE DID
A GARAGE, CAN IT GO
ON A SLAB?
ABSOLUTELY.
BUT IT WILL STILL BE
TO HAVE THE
FOUR FOOT FOUNDATION
ON THE GROUND.
YEAH. YEAH. YOU HAVE
TO HAVE FOUR FEET OF
FROST PROTECTION.
NO, NO HERE'S MY
OTHER
QUESTION. YEAH
SEPTIC.
TELL ME YEAH, I WAS
WANT TO
DO THE ONE FOR THE
HOUSE
IS ONLY A THOUSAND
YEAH,
I'LL TELL YOU IT
WAS BUILT IN 84.
YEAH, SO IT'S I'M
THINKING ABOUT
UPGRADING
AND THEN HITTING ON
TO IT. CORRECT. IS
THERE
A SETBACK? FROM
MAXIMUM AS FAR
AS THAT GOES BECAUSE
I'M
MAXIMUM DISTANCE NO,
THERE'S NO MAXIMUM
DISTANCE.
THE THING WE'LL RUN
INTO IS PITCH
THAT WE HIRE WHERE
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
THE PITCH
RIGHT NOW WE CAN GO
REALLY LOW
ON THE PITCH IF WE
USE A SIX
INCH PIPE. OKAY, SO
WE CAN GET DOWN TO
UH
TWO PERCENT.
OKAY, WHICH IS UH A
LITTLE
OVER AN EIGHTH OF AN
INCH PER
FOOT IF WE USE SIX
INCH YES,
WELL WE CAN DO
IT 100% BUT
THE SECRET TO THAT
IS WE GOT TO MAKE
SURE THAT PIPE'S
PERFECT SO WOULD YOU
TAKE CARE OF THE
ENGINEERING?
OH EVERYTHING. YEAH.
YEAH NEW OLD STUFF.
CORRECT YEAH,
AND DOES IT INCLUDE
THOSE
PRICES, APPLIANCES
ALSO?
EVERYTHING IS
INCLUDED, IT'S A
GOOD QUESTION,
EVERYTHING IS
INCLUDED
EXCEPT FOR THE
APPLIANCES, AND I'LL
TELL YOU WHY. I USED
TO DO AN
APPLIANCE ALLOWANCE,
AND EVERYBODY
WOULD JUST SAY,
THAT'S TOO HIGH
OR TOO LOW, SO NOW I
SAY, WHATEVER
YOU BRING ME, I'M
GOING TO PUT
IT IN AND MAKE SURE
IT WORKS.
BUY AN EXTENDED
WARRANTY,
BUT EVERYTHING ELSE,
THE REST, EVERYTHING
ELSE IN THAT HOUSE
IS INSURED,
EXCUSE ME,
EVERYTHING
ELSE IN THAT HOUSE
IS WARRANTY FOR
THREE YEARS.
SO, WHAT VALUE ARE
YOU
BRINGING? ARE YOU
PRE-BUILDING
THESE IN A FACTORY?
NO,
ABSOLUTELY
NOT. THESE ARE
STICK-BUILT, YEAH.
AND THE REASON
I DO THAT IS BECAUSE
I BUILD IT EXACTLY
THE WAY YOU WANT IT.
YOU KNOW,
IF YOU WANT IT, YOU
KNOW,
23 FOOT, TWO AND A
HALF INCHES
LONG, I'M GOING TO
MAKE
IT THAT WAY. YOU
KNOW,
AGAIN, THERE'S
NOTHING
WRONG WITH MODULAR,
JUST
A DIFFERENT PRODUCT.
AND YOU
ARE LIMITED.
RIGHT. BECAUSE
YOU'RE BASICALLY
TAKING TWO BOXES
AND WHAT ARE YOU
GUYS
RUNNING RIGHT NOW
FOR
TIMELINES? A FIGURE
FROM A DEAD START,
FIGURE NINE MONTHS
BETWEEN PERMITS AND
BUILD. YEP.
AND A LOT OF IT IS,
YOU KNOW,
AS A WET LENS, YOU
KNOW,
DO WE HAVE TO
COMBINE LOTS,
AS AN 81X PLANT,
YOU KNOW, THERE'S A
LOT OF DISCOVERY
THAT WE HAVE TO, YOU
KNOW,
BUT IT'S BEEN
RUNNING, YOU KNOW,
AND AGAIN, A LOT OF
THAT'S DEPENDING
ON YOU, YOU KNOW, DO
YOU KNOW WHAT
YOU WANT TO BUILD?
DO YOU KNOW THE
PLAN?
OK, I DO HAVE A
QUESTION
FOR YOU ON YOUR
SMALLER FLORIDA VAN.
YEAH.
SO NINE ARE
THE ARE LIKE, ARE
THEY
ABLE TO GET
FINANCING ON THAT?
OH, YEAH. SQUARE
FOOTAGE BEING
SO SMALL. YEAH, NO,
NO PROBLEM AT
ALL. OK. YEAH.
YEAH, WE HAVE
MAKE SURE YOU SHOOT
ME AN EMAIL
BECAUSE I WILL SAY I
HAVE
A SHEET IS SOME GET
ALL THE LENDERS
AND THE LAWYERS
AND ALL ON ONE
SHEET. OK. SO
YEAH. ALL THE TAXES,
DOES
IT AFFECT THEIR
TAXES?
IT WILL. IT'LL
SHOW US ITS OWN LINE
ITEM NOW.
OK. YEAH. SO IT'S
EASY MATH TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT
IT'S GOING TO BE.
YOU
JUST LOOK AT THE TAX
BILL.
RIGHT. AND IT'LL BE
BROKEN
DOWN LAND AND HOUSE
SEPARATE.
RIGHT. YOU TAKE THE
PART THEY
CHARGE YOU FOR THE
HOUSE, HOW
MUCH THEY'RE
CHARGING PER SQUARE
FOOT
OF THE HOUSE, AND
JUST DO THE MATH AND
SAY, OK, IT'S
A 900 SQUARE FEET.
AGAIN, THIS IS
A MADE UP NUMBER.
THEY CHARGE IN
$5,000 A YEAR.
SO IT COMES UP TO $3
A SQUARE
FOOT. AND THEN YOU
JUST SAY,
OK, I'M BUILDING 900
SQUARE FOOT ADU
TIMES 300.
THAT'S WHAT I'M
GOING TO PAY
IN TAXES. OK. $3.
EXCUSE
ME. IT'S EASY MATH.
ONCE
I PULL THE TAX BILL,
I CAN DO
THE MATH FOR YOU.
RIGHT.
JUST FOR ELECTRICITY
AND
ALL THAT. SEPARATE.
RIGHT. THE ONLY
THING IS,
IF I COUNTED DOWN,
IT DOES
CHARGE FOR SEWER AND
WATER.
SO WE'D HAVE TO JUST
WORK SOMETHING
OUT. WELL, WE CAN DO
A PRIVATE WATER
METER INSIDE THE ADU
IF YOU'D
LIKE. OH, WE'RE
TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT.
SO YOU CAN DO THE
MATH YOURSELF. OK.